Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Photographs 6169 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Photographs
0000-2999
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees (NUHHCE)
Local 1199 Drug amd Hospital Union
6169 P
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Photographs.
5830507
Biographical / Historical
As a local of the Drug, Hospital, and Health Care Employees Union, Local 1199 was founded by Leon J. Davis in 1932, to organize pharmacists in New York City. Nonprofessional hospital employees were organized starting in 1958.
Because of the large number of Black and Puerto Rican workers it sparked the first postware Civil Rights Movement. May 8, 1959 marks the start of approximately 3500 hospital workers striking against seven large private hospitals in New York City, the strike lasted forty-six days.
Professional and technical workes were added to the union in 1963, the same year they won the right to collective bargaining under provisions of the state's labor relations act. The union was granted the right to represent workers across the state in 1965. Registered nurses became part of the union in 1973.
In 1998 the union became part of SEIU and membership went up significantly.
Scope and Contents
This collection has photographs of various union members that were used for displays. There are also more photographs of union members that weren't chosen for any displays, as well as conference photographs.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5929: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Records 5929 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio-Visual Materials 5929 MB: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Memorabilia 5929 P: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Photographs 6069: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Additional Files 6084 G: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Women of Hope Poster Sets 6085 G: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project "Frederick Douglass and His Time" Posters 6089 G: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Posters 6140: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project 6140 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio Recordings 6169: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Files 6169 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio-Visual Materials 6169 MB: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Memorabilia
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheelref@cornell.edu https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 03, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 27, 2015
Foner, Moe, 1915-; Bread and Roses Cultural Project -- Photographs; National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees; National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees. Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Union (New York, N.Y.) --Photographs
5830507
- Certificates used as part of a photo display (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  *The Samuel Rubin Health and Social Justice Award *Certificate of Award Moe Foner Is Hereby Awarded This Certificate of Award for Outstanding Accomplishments * Parsons School of Design of New School University, Honorary Degree of Doctor of Fine Arts, Conferred Upon Moe Foner *New Jersey General Assembly *Parsons School of Design of New School University, To All Persons to whom this writing may come, Greeting
- Display photo (African-American Hospital Worker) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Display Photo (Hospital employee and patient) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Display Photo (Custodian mopping) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Photo Display (folks holding hands singing) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Photo Display (African-American Laundry Worker) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Photo Display (African-American Mechanic) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Photo Display (photo of female speaker) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Photo Display (1199 Labor Day Street Fair) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Photo Display (women assisting a man dressing) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Display Photo (Union member) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Photo Display (African-American Union member) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Display Photo (Laundry Worker) (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Display Photo (Woman and baby) (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Photo Display (African-American hospital employee) (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Display Photo (African-American Union member) (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Display Photo (African-American man, Recognition Certificate attached on the back "Women of Hope to Moe Foner") (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Display Photo (Man typing) (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Lawrence 1912 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  slide 1-20
- Lawrence 1912 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  slide 21-40
- Lawrence 1912 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  slide 41-60
- Lawrence 1912 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  slide 61-80
- Lawrence 1912 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  slide 81-100
- Lawrence 1912 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  slide 101-120
- Lawrence 1912 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  slide 121-133
- The Pride is Back (Box 2, Folder 8)
  15 misc. slides
- The Pride is Back (Box 2, Folder 9)
  20 slides
- The Pride is back (Box 2, Folder 10)
- The Pride is Back (Box 2, Folder 11)
- The Pride is Back (Box 2, Folder 12)
- The Pride is Back (Box 2, Folder 13)
- The Pride is Back (Box 2, Folder 14)
  19 slides
- Occupational Dermatoses (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Occupational Dermatoses (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Occupational Dermatoses (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Occupational Dermatoses (Box 2, Folder 18)
  slide 61-77
- Ten Years (Box 2, Folder 20)
  18 slides
- Ten Years (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Ten years (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Ten Years (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Ten Years (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Ten Years (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Ten Years (Box 2, Folder 26)
  24 slides
- Pilgrim Press - Bread + Roses pictures - not used (Box 2, Folder 28)
  26 photographs
- Pilgrim Press - Bread + Roses Pictures - not used (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Pilgrim Press - Bread + Roses Pictures - not used (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Pilgrim Press - Bread + Roses Pictures - not used (Box 2, Folder 31)
  2 photo copies
- 'Take Care, Take Care' - Publicity (Box 3, Folder 1)
  14 photographs -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 32
- 'Take Care, Take Care' - Publicity (Box 3, Folder 2)
  -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 33
- Home Care Workers of the Year (Box 3, Folder 3)
  1 photograph -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 34
- Ralph Fasanella - Photos (Box 3, Folder 4)
  2 photographs -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 35
- Conference - Not Bread Alone (Box 3, Folder 5)
  negatives -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 36
- Langston Hughes (Box 3, Folder 6)
  negatives -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 37
- Working (Box 3, Folder 7)
  14 slides; 1 photograph -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 38
- Labor Morals (Box 3, Folder 8)
  1 slide, 3 photographs -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 39
- Haitian Art (Box 3, Folder 9)
  3 photographs -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 40
- 'Like a Beautiful Child - current photo (Box 3, Folder 10)
  10 photographs -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 41
- Moe Foner Picture (Box 3, Folder 11)
  6 photographs -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 42
- 'I am somebody' (Box 3, Folder 12)
  20 photographs -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 43
- Take Care/National Union Convention Photographs (Box 3, Folder 13)
  15 slides -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 44
- Take Care/National Union Convention photographs (Box 3, Folder 14)
  19 slides -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 45
- Take Care/National Union Convention Photographs (Box 3, Folder 15)
  21 slides -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 46
- Take Care/National Union Convention photographs (Box 3, Folder 16)
  4 photographs -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 47
- Take Care III (Box 3, Folder 17)
  1 photograph -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 48
- Georgianna Johnson (Box 3, Folder 18)
  2 photographs -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 49
- 1199 Gallery - 'Rican/Structions' by Juan Sanchez: Jan.-Feb. '95 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  2 photographs -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 50
- Photos for book: 'Lawrence 1912' (Box 3, Folder 20)
  -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 51
- Photos for Conference - 1917 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  26 photographs -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 52
- Photos for Conference - 1917 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  26 photographs -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 53
- Photos for Conference - 1917 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  25 photographs -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 54
- Photos for Conference - 1917 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  20 photographs -- collection was re-organized -- was formerly box 2, ff 55
- Occupational Dermatoses (Box 4)
  accompanying cassette
- Ten Years (Box 5)
- Ten years (Box 6)
  2nd of 2 cassettes removed with folder 27 from box 2